For you to so easily forget something I've given you...
is punishable by death, Araragi-kun.
Yeah, sorry about that.
I'm not going to forgive you, even if you apologize.
I did come chasing after you to make fun of you, though.
Did you get hit by a car or something?
There's something over there that resembles your precious bike,
which is pretty beaten up, or should I say, rammed into a telephone pole.
Unless you were hit by a convoy of trucks, how would that happen?
No, I just fell on my own.
I was on the phone, pedaling,
and I ended up crashing into the telephone pole.
Oh, I see.
But for you to crash into a sturdy concrete wall with enough force to destroy it,
and end up with merely these wounds,
is rather commendable, Araragi-kun.
I assume you don't need an ambulance?
Yeah, I'll be able to move again after I rest a bit.
I see.
Then, I'll do you a big favor.
Think happy thoughts until you're able to move around again.
Go on in, Araragi-senpai.
Sorry, it's a little messy.
No need to hold back, you know.
I really admire that you're sensitive enough to hesitate before entering the room of a girl you barely know,
but it's probably not the best time to be worrying about that.
Yeah...
Kanbaru.
What's up?
One hour-no, thirty minutes is fine...
Just give me some time to clean up this room.
Okay.
So,
where should I start, Araragi-senpai?
Well, at any rate,
please allow me to apologize for last night.
Yeah...
Like I thought, that was you...
Saying things like "like I thought"
really makes you sound irritated, Araragi-senpai.
You completely saw through it, right?
If you didn't,
then there's no way you'd come to talk to me.
Not really,
it was just a guess.
I came to my conclusion based on your build, outline, and silhouette.
I also considered who'd know about my study session with Senjougahara.
I searched after narrowing it down with those factors.
If you think of it like that, well, yeah...
Hmm, I see.
Nice insight.
They say that there are guys who can differentiate girls based on their waists...
can you do that too?
Sorry about that.
That wasn't my intention...
Well, even if you apologize...
What I really want to know is the reason.
Well, actually, even more than the reason, that power...
I want to ask about that superhuman strength...
What exactly do you...
I guess if I was to start somewhere,
I guess it'd have to be from there...
All right.
Araragi-senpai, first I'd like to ask you
if you're the type of person that can believe in things that seem crazy.
Things that seem crazy?
Do you not get it?
Basically, I'm asking if you can believe in what you see with your own eyes.
I don't believe in anything but what I've seen with my own eyes.
I've come this far believing everything that I've seen.
That includes what happened to Senjougahara, too, of course.
Oh, you had that figured out too?
Senjougahara, from the track and field club, and you, from the basketball club,
were called the Valhalla Combination, right?
That's right!
Wow, I'm surprised you even know about that, Araragi-senpai.
I know where it comes from, too.
It's a well thought out name.
Isn't it? I thought of it.
She thought of it herself...
It's been a while since I've felt this miserable.
But yeah, putting the Valhalla Combination aside,
Senjougahara-senpai and I have always, since middle school...
No...
Before I talk anymore about that,
there's something I need you to look at.
Honestly, it's not something I really want others to see.
After all, I am still a girl.
Well, this is it...
It looks like...
a monkey's paw...
Araragi-senpai, you really have unfathomably discerning eyes.
I'm amazed. Being able to tell what this is with just a glance... there's no word for how surprising that is.
Stop deciding everything I do is impressive!
I'm just telling you my impressions of what I see.
It's nothing special.
Oh, really?
The Monkey's Paw is the title of a short story by William Wymark Jacobs.
It's said that it grants the owner's wishes, but in a way that conflicts with what they really intended.
Never heard of it.
Being able to see the truth behind this without knowing anything,
I can't help but think you're chosen by someone in heaven!
I-Is it okay if I touch it?
Yeah.
It's fine right now.
I-I see.
It's alive.
This is the living type of aberration after all.
Don't make weird noises!
It's because you touched it weirdly!
I did not touch it weirdly!
I'm ticklish.
Even so, don't make sounds that completely change impressions of you!
Oh, come on.
As you can see, it moves how I want it to right now,
but there are times when it won't.
No, that's not quite right.
I guess I should say it moves against my will.
Against your will?
Well, not really my will, but...
Hmm, I guess this is hard to understand.
In other words, Araragi-senpai,
the one who attacked you last night was definitely me,
but I have no recollection of it, for the most part.
It was as if I was half asleep, or half dreaming...
It's not like I don't remember it at all, but...
Trance...
That's called a trance.
I know about it.
The type of aberration that manipulates human works by desynchronizing the body and the mind.
Wow, you really know a lot, Araragi-senpai.
I see. So it's called an aberration.
Well, it's not like I know that much about it either.
I'm not sure why, but lately I've been experiencing things like that a lot.
And there's this guy that knows a lot about that stuff.
Yeah, I see.
I'm glad you're an understanding person.
We wouldn't have been able to have this conversation if you'd run away after seeing my arm.
And I probably would've been hurt a little, too.
Even so, I really was a bit surprised.
But since you told me the most surprising part to start off with,
I'm fairly confident that I won't be surprised by anything you tell me now.
Great!
Of course, that's exactly the reason I showed you my arm first.
You got through the most difficult part at the very beginning.
All right, I think I'll get on to the real topic then.
I'm a lesbian.
I guess that might've been a bit blunt, since you're a guy.
Umm...
Let me rephrase it: I'm a homose-
Those are exactly the same!
Wait, what?! What do you mean?
You're saying that you and Senjougahara were known as the Valhalla Combination in middle school,
and Senjougahara refers to you as that girl,
and she said yesterday that she'd never broken up with a guy before...
Are you saying that you mean...?!
That's not it.
Senjougahara-senpai was my unrequited love.
To me, Senjougahara-senpai is pure and perfect.
She was someone I adored.
I was satisfied by just being near her.
Senjougahara-senpai was popular with everyone,
but I think my feelings stood apart compared to those people.
I'm confident about that.
I even thought that I could die for Senjougahara-senpai's sake.
But...
Senjougahara-senpai changed.
She became different.
I'd heard that she fell ill after she got to high school.
I'd also heard that she stopped track and field because of a prolonged illness.
But I'd never have thought she'd change that much.
I thought it was just a bad rumor.
But I was wrong.
It was even worse than the rumor.
There was something much more alarming happening to her body.
Once I realized that, I knew I had to do something.
I knew I had to save her.
It's natural, don't you agree?
We were in different clubs and different classes in middle school,
but she treated me really kindly.
So, this time,
I was the one who tried to save her.
I could do something about her problem.
Even if I couldn't, I could be by her side and heal her heart.
That's what I thought.
I was hopelessly rejected.
"I don't even think of you as an underclassman, let alone as a friend."
"Not now and not ever."
She said that clearly to me.
So from then on, I've kept my distance from her.
Since that was the one and only thing she had ever wanted from me...
Of course, I couldn't forget about her...
But if that would save her even the tiniest bit,
then I could accept it.
You...
But a year went by, and I found out about you.
You were talking to her one morning quite closely in the classroom.
Even during middle school, she'd never talked to me with that kind of...
happy smile.
Do you get it?!
You were doing something that I really, really wanted to do, but had given up on
like it was perfectly natural!
Kanbaru!
No, that was...
At first, I was jealous.
I tried to rethink my feelings,
but in the end, I was still jealous of you.
I wondered why I wasn't good enough.
I wondered if it would be different if I were a guy.
I wondered if it was because I was a girl.
Maybe she didn't need an underclassman or even a friend,
but wanted a lover.
If that was the case, why couldn't it be me?!
I was jealous of you, and I was disappointed with her.
And I was on the verge of giving up on someone like myself.
To hell with healing her pain... to hell with keeping my distance from her...
Was I seriously thinking that she was going to praise me for doing that?!
That's ridiculous!
How could I be that hypocritical?!
But...
Even then...
I wanted her to treat me kindly like she used to...
Maybe it's just selfish, but I want to be near her no matter what.
So that's why...
So that's why I asked this paw to grant my wish.
I want to be by her side.
So that person's name is Oshino Meme?
Is "Meme" written in katakana?
Yeah.
Although, he's not as cute as his name suggests.
If we don't hurry, the sun will set before we get there.
Your left hand is dangerous at night, right?
Yeah, though really, it's actually that there's no problem when the sun is out.
At least for the next few hours, it should be fine.
Araragi-senpai, there's one thing I want to ask you.
What is it?
What part of Senjougahara-senpai captivated you?
I mean, she was your classmate for over two years, and you guys never even talked.
W-Why would you ask that?
In other words, if you're after her body, I think I can be of service instead.
I think I'm fairly cute.
If I let my hair grow a little bit, I think I'd be a bit more girly,
and I also maintain my skin well.
Plus, I've been playing sports for a long time.
My waist is just narrow enough, and my body is nice and tight overall.
I'm completely serious.
If you wish so,
I'll be the bottom to your top anytime, anywhere.
Top...?! Bottom...?!
Why the hell would I wish for that?!
Oh, I see. You don't know anything about BL.
That's surprising.
I don't want to talk about BL with an underclassman girl!
BL is short for boys' love, you know.
I know! I'm not misunderstanding you!
Yeah, I noticed it when I was cleaning her room.
You're not misunderstanding me?
Then, what exactly are you angry about, Araragi-senpai?
Don't tell me you like the bottom!
Shut up!
This conversation is over!
Forgive me for being intrusive, Araragi-senpai,
but I think that you won't survive in the world
if you can't even enjoy a dirty conversation with an underclassman girl.
I really don't want to be counseled by an underclassman girl.
Even if you say that, Araragi-senpai,
it's problematic that you desire chaste girls when that desire is based on unfounded fantasies.
It can't be helped.
Even girls are interested in talking about dirty stuff.
All right, you can go ahead and continue telling me whether you wear boxers or briefs.
I never said anything about that.
What?
Were we talking about whether or not I'm wearing panties under my spats?
Aren't you wearing them?! Kanbaru-san!
So under the spats coming out from the bottom of your skirt is...
Even if that was the case, there's no need to be surprised, is there?
Spats were originally intended to be lingerie, you know.
That's all the more of a reason!
Isn't that the same as flashing your underwear around every day?!
Hmm, if you put it that way, I suppose it's true.
Well, I guess for the time being
we'll just say it was a stylish present from this sports-loving girl.
No!
That's just plain exhibitionist perversion!
Oh yeah, now I remember!
That's not what we were talking about either.
We were talking about whether I could be Senjougahara-senpai's replacement.
Hold it!
Don't change subjects before stating it clearly!
Are you wearing them, or aren't you?!
Say it clearly!
Let's not concern ourselves with such vulgar details, Araragi-senpai.
It's a trivial matter.
Like hell it is!
It's the difference between my underclassman being a sports girl or an exhibitionist!
Let's see...
What if you think of if this way:
She's both a sports girl and an exhibitionist.
For someone who believes she's a sports girl, she is a sports girl,
and for someone who believes she's an exhibitionist, she's an exhibitionist.
Don't play with words!
It's both A and B.
For someone who believes it's A, it's A,
and for someone who believes it's B, it's B.
That's only cool until middle school!
Are you my little sister or something?!
But seriously, Kanbaru, no matter how hard you try,
you can never be a replacement for Senjougahara.
You're not Senjougahara.
It's impossible for someone to replace someone else.
Just like it's impossible for someone to become someone else.
No matter how much you like them...
No matter how much you adore them.
That's true.
It's just as you said.
Yeah.
All right, let's stop with the idle talk and get going already.
H-Hey, Araragi-senpai,
what was with that girl?
She was super cute!
Why does that give you the biggest smile you've had all day?
I want to hug her.
No, I want her to hug me!
But anyway, you're better off not getting involved with that.
You're late, Araragi-kun!
I was so tired of waiting that I was about to fall asleep.
What's this, Araragi-kun?
I see you brought yet a different girl today.
You bring a different girl every time I see you.
I'm happy for you.
Shut up.
Stop saying the same thing every time I come.
Oh yeah, I saw Shinobu on the stairway.
What's she doing out there?
Oh, she sulked off when I ate one of the donuts from Mister Donut.
She's been like that since yesterday.
What kind of vampire is she?
Oshino, this is Kanbaru Suruga, one year behind me in school.
Kanbaru is written with the characters god and plains.
As for Suruga, um...
It's Suruga from Japanese bondage torture.
Oh, Japanese bondage torture, huh?
Got it, got it.
I'm Araragi-senpai's underclassman. Nice to meet you.
Nice to meet you, too.
I'm Oshino Meme, miss.
If you're his underclassman, then you should also be an underclassman of that tsundere girl, am I right?
Oshino, anyway, I'll start off by giving this to you.
It's from that tsundere girl, Senjougahara.
Oh right, money.
Money, money...
That's great.
It was just about to start affecting my lifestyle.
So, what's up with that young lady?
Oh, it's those bandages, isn't it?
Oshino-san, I'm...
Let's start from the beginning.
It doesn't really seem to be an enjoyable story.
Stories about arms never are.
It's especially true in my case, and all the more if it's the left arm.
Could you take off the bandages and let me see it, miss?
Oh, sure.
Is this good enough?
Yup, it is.
I see, just as I thought.
Araragi-kun, and you too, miss... let me clear something up for you:
Your left hand-that's not a monkey's paw.
Huh?
The monkey's paw assimilating with the owner
is something that I've never heard of.
Miss, your hand was originally mummified, right?
If that has gained life by assimilating with you,
then I'd say for the time being that it's probably the Rainy Devil.
Rainy?
Yeah, it's a low-level demon.
If you narrow that group down to ones that have a monkey's arms and wear a raincoat,
the number necessarily decreases quite a bit.
The only one that assimilates with the owner is the Rainy Devil.
It's not a monkey's paw-it's a demon's hand.
Of course, it will grant you anything you wish for...
I mean, after all, it's a trade for your soul.
Your soul?
In exchange for taking your soul it grants you three wishes.
It's only natural.
For demons, that is...
I'm Karen!
And I'm Tsukihi!
Tsukihi-chan, you're in the tea club, right?
Yeah, I am the tea club!
Well then, do you know what type of tea they use in Uji city in Kyoto?
I know, I know!
In Uji they have tea on tap!
Really?
By the way, a tap and a jacuzzi resemble each other in the position of their names, eh?
You're well-versed in discussing Uji City.
It's preview quiz!
Quiz!
Preview Izu!
Izu?
Izu is a riddle!
Izu is a riddle?
Next time, "Suruga Monkey", Part Three!
Izu is a quiz!
Enigmatic!